["Drunken Sailor" plays]
【《醉水手》播放】
* *
**
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
- I got some fresh ingredients
for our new Krabby Soup.
- 我有一些新鲜的食材
为我们新推出的蟹黄汤。
A half-eaten Krabby Patty...
吃了一半的蟹肉饼……
[splash]
[溅]
Two moldy pickles...
两个发霉的泡菜...
[splash]
[溅]
And some smashed potatoes
that look like Squidward.
还有一些土豆泥
看起来像章鱼哥。
[splash]
[溅]
* *
**
- Mr. Krabs, did you get
those ingredients
- 蟹老板，你收到了吗？
那些成分
from the trash?
从垃圾中？
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Of course not!
当然不是！
That wouldn't be legal.
那是不合法的。
I intercepted these items
on their way to the trash.
我截获了这些物品
在去垃圾箱的路上。
I want everybody in
Bikini Bottom to buy my soup.
我希望每个人都在
比基尼泳裤给我买汤。
Yuppies, guppies, puppies...
雅皮士、孔雀鱼、小狗……
- Hippies?
- 嬉皮士？
[growls]
[咆哮]
- Yeah, there's a group
of hippies living out back
- 是的，有一个团体
住在后面的嬉皮士
by the hydrothermal vent.
通过热液喷口。
- Hippies?
- 嬉皮士？
On my property?
在我的财产上？
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
* *
**
All right,
you longhairs, beat it!
好吧，
你们这些长毛，打败它！
This here's private property!
这里是私人财产！
- We're just keeping warm, dude.
- 我们只是为了取暖，伙计。
- Yeah, baby.
- 是的，宝贝。
We like to hang near
hydrothermal vents.
我们喜欢靠近
热液喷口。
- Oof!
- 噢！
- We're vent creatures.
- 我们是发泄生物。
We get cold real fast.
我们很快就冷了。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Yeah, I don't care.
- 是的，我不在乎。
You're trespassing.
你这是非法侵入。
And littering paisleys!
还有乱扔佩斯利图案的！
Ha-ha, back, back you go--oof!
哈哈，回来了，回来了——哎呀！
[bell ringing]
[铃声响起]
- Hey, freaky friends,
it's warm in here.
- 嘿，奇怪的朋友们，
这里很温暖。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[pop]
[流行音乐]
[shattering]
[破碎]
And keep running, you deadbeats!
继续跑吧，你们这些赖账者！
- This seems just as good
as a heat vent.
- 这看起来也不错
作为散热口。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Let's crash this pad.
- 让我们破坏这个垫子。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[splash]
[溅]
[crackling]
[爆裂声]
- That should discourage
those bohemians.
- 这应该劝阻
那些波西米亚人。
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
- Hey, hold on there, lad.
- 嘿，坚持住，小伙子。
You might be overdoing
the ingredients.
你可能做得太过分了
成分。
* *
**
[slurps]
[啜饮]
Huh, it's just broth.
呵呵，只是汤而已。
- Huh, that's funny.
- 哈，这很有趣。
It was loaded with stuff
a few minutes ago.
里面装满了东西
几分钟前。
- Hmm, well, go ahead
and add some more.
- 嗯，好吧，继续吧
并添加更多。
We got customers waiting.
我们有顾客在等待。
- Aye, aye, Mr. Krabs.
- 是的，是的，蟹老板。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[whistles]
[口哨声]
[splash]
[溅]
- [chomps]
- [咀嚼]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [chomps]
- [咀嚼]
- Hmm, guess I bought
the disappearing
- 嗯，我猜我买了
消失的
kind of potatoes.
一种土豆。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- [chomps]
- [咀嚼]
* *
**
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- Hmm?
- 唔？
Oh...
哦...
Oh, hungry soup, eh?
哦，饿了喝汤吧？
Let's see if you like onions.
看看你喜不喜欢洋葱。
* *
**
Today's special is
onion soup a la SpongeBob.
今天的特别是
海绵宝宝洋葱汤。
Oh!
哦！
All right, listen, soup.
好吧，听着，汤。
You want me to get tough?
你想让我变得强硬吗？
[grunts]
[咕哝]
All right, I'll get tough!
好吧，我会变强的！
I made you from scratch,
and I can unscratch you!
我从零开始创造了你
我可以帮你除掉伤痕！
[crack]
[裂缝]
Whoa, whoa!
哇哦！
- When you're done fighting
with the food,
- 当你结束战斗时
和食物一起，
we have an order
for three soups.
我们有订单
三汤。
- [chewing]
- [咀嚼]
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
Make soup, not war.
煮汤，不是战争。
[splash]
[溅]
- Well, I never.
- 嗯，我从来没有。
* *
**
- Ah--Achoo!
- 啊--阿呼！
[blows nose]
[擤鼻子]
[splash]
[溅]
- Mwah!
- 哇！
[whack]
[重击]
- You obviously love your soup
more than you love me!
- 你显然很喜欢你的汤
胜过你爱我！
- Take this soup back!
- 把这汤拿回来！
- I'm returning
my husband's soup too!
- 我回来了
还有我老公的汤！
- [blows a raspberry]
- [吹覆盆子]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[splash]
[溅]
- What's the problem?
- 有什么问题吗？
- There are hippies in the soup!
- 汤里有嬉皮士！
- Hah, hippies in the soup.
- 哈，汤里的嬉皮士。
That's a new one.
那是一个新的。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- Avast there, ye invertebrate!
- 在那里，无脊椎动物！
You're throwing away me money.
你把钱扔给我。
- Anyone else down there?
- 下面还有其他人吗？
- Hmm, Mr. Krabs, I think
the soup might be haunted.
- 嗯，蟹老板，我想
汤可能闹鬼了。
- Son, did you forget
to pay your brain bill again?
- 儿子，你忘了吗
再次支付你的大脑账单吗？
* *
**
[splash]
[溅]
- Wh--What?
- 什——什么？
both: [gasp]
两人：[喘气]
hippies: Hey, hey, Mr. K,
how much money
嬉皮士：嘿嘿，K先生，
多少钱
did you make today?
今天你做了吗？
[splash]
[溅]
- Oh, you hippies!
- 哦，你们这些嬉皮士！
[bang]
[砰]
All right, you deadbeats!
好吧，你们这些死人！
This is an eviction.
这是驱逐。
You are to leave
this soup immediately.
你要离开
立即喝这个汤。
Huh?
Whoa!
啊？
哇！
hippies: Heck no, we won't go!
嬉皮士：哎呀，不，我们不会去！
all: Heck no, we won't go!
Heck no, we won't go!
所有人：哎呀，不，我们不会去！
哎呀不，我们不会去！
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
all: Heck no, we won't go!
所有人：哎呀，不，我们不会去！
- Sorry, Mr. Krabs,
it's just so catchy.
- 对不起，蟹老板先生，
真是太吸引人了。
- [chuckles]
Why don't you just
- [轻笑]
你为什么不直接
dump the soup out?
把汤倒掉？
- And lose all the money
I've already put into it?
- 并失去所有的钱
我已经投入了？
Heck no!
They gotta go!
哎呀不！
他们得走了！
* *
**
- Whatcha using for bait?
- 用什么做诱饵？
- Something hippies love--
long hair.
- 嬉皮士喜欢的东西--
长头发。
- [inhales]
- Shh!
- [吸气]
- 嘘！
I got one!
- Ooh!
我得到了一个！
- 哦！
* *
**
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
Hippies can't resist
playing with this little
嬉皮士无法抗拒
玩这个小
crochet foot bag.
钩针脚袋。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Neither can I!
- 我也不能！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Resist the temptation, dude.
- 抵制诱惑，伙计。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Aww, but we can't let
that little bag
- 哇，但我们不能让
那个小袋子
hit the ground, man!
撞到地上了，伙计！
- Hah!
- 哈！
[splashing]
[溅]
- Cool, man, you saved the sack
from gravity, like, forever.
- 太酷了，伙计，你救了我的命
远离重力，就像永远一样。
- Beautiful, man.
- 美丽，伙计。
[rhythmic music]
[节奏音乐]
- Mr. Krabs, why are we
in a drum circle?
- 蟹老板，我们为什么
在鼓圈里？
- It's something
that all hippies
- 这是一些东西
所有嬉皮士
are required to participate in.
都需要参加。
* *
**
[rattling]
[嘎嘎声]
* *
**
- [laughs]
Dig that beat.
- [笑]
挖掘那个节拍。
- Oh, that is
a wild drum circle, dudes.
- 哦，那就是
狂野的鼓圈，伙计们。
- [panting]
My hands are starting to hurt.
- [气喘吁吁]
我的手开始痛了。
- Couldn't we have gotten
softer drums?
-我们难道不能得到
更柔和的鼓？
* *
**
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
I'm out.
我出去了。
Oof.
钱币。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Me too.
- 我也是。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Get up, you tender palms!
It's working!
- 起来吧，你那温柔的手掌！
它正在工作！
[rhythmic music]
[节奏音乐]
* *
**
[groaning]
[呻吟]
* *
**
[shattering]
[破碎]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Oh, my claws!
哦，我的爪子！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
My claws.
我的爪子。
I wish we had another drummer.
我希望我们有另一个鼓手。
- I've got a drummer, Mr. Krabs.
- 我有一个鼓手，蟹老板。
[tapping]
[窃听]
hippies: [grunt]
嬉皮士：[咕哝]
- Oh, man!
- 哦，伙计！
Drum machines ain't cool.
鼓机并不酷。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[splashing]
[溅]
- [yells]
- [大喊]
- It's your job
to go into that soup
- 这是你的工作
进入那个汤
and remove those hippies.
并除去那些嬉皮士。
[splash]
[溅]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- [gentle breathing]
- [轻柔的呼吸]
[smooth music]
[流畅的音乐]
[tires screech]
[轮胎尖叫声]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[laughs]
[笑]
Hello, I'm SpongeBob.
大家好，我是海绵宝宝。
- Dude, it's a square.
- 老兄，这是一个正方形。
- No, man, it's that crazy cook
that's been feeding us.
- 不，伙计，是那个疯狂的厨师
那一直在养活我们。
- Have some carrot
love beads, SpongeBob.
- 吃点胡萝卜
爱珠子，海绵宝宝。
- [chomp]
Mm, thank you!
- [咀嚼]
嗯，谢谢！
Oh, Mr. Krabs sent me here
to tell you guys
噢，蟹老板派我来的
告诉你们
you have to leave.
你必须离开。
- Old Man Krabs
needs to mellow out.
- 蟹老翁
需要变得柔和。
- Yeah, he should
try meditation.
- 是的，他应该
尝试冥想。
- Ooh, like this?
- 哦，像这样吗？
- Hey, you're far out.
- 嘿，你差得太远了。
* *
**
- It's cool.
Up is down.
- 这很酷。
上则下。
Down is up.
It's all relative.
下即是上。
这都是相对的。
Relative.
相对的。
- Oh, wow, SpongeBob,
you just blew our minds.
- 哦，哇，海绵宝宝，
你让我们大吃一惊。
* *
**
[shimmering]
[闪烁]
* *
**
- Son, how's
the eviction going?
- 儿子，怎么样
驱逐进展如何？
- Oh, wow, you're beautiful.
- 哦，哇，你真漂亮。
- [gasps]
You went too deep!
- [喘气]
你入戏太深了！
You've gone full flower child.
你已经变成了一个十足的花童。
Oh, no!
哦，不！
* *
**
- What's happening, man?
- 发生什么事了，伙计？
- Patrick, what are you
doing here?
- 帕特里克，你是什么？
在这里做什么？
- Just tubing down the river
of life, baby.
- 只是顺流而下
生命的意义，宝贝。
[chomp]
[咀嚼]
- Does Mr. Krabs know
you're in here?
- 蟹老板知道吗
你在这儿吗？
* *
**
- No Krabs.
- 没有螃蟹。
[chomp]
[咀嚼]
[spits]
[吐口水]
Can't stand those things.
受不了那些东西。
- Oh, oh, suddenly everything's
becoming very confusing.
- 哦，哦，突然一切都变了
变得非常混乱。
I--I--I know.
我——我——我知道。
I'll have a Krabby Patty.
我要一份蟹肉饼。
That always calms me down.
这总是让我平静下来。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Ahh!
啊！
Huh?
啊？
Hello?
你好？
Anybody here?
这里有人吗？
Whoa, how long
was I in that soup?
哇，多久了
我在那汤里吗？
Mr. Krabs, is that you?
蟹老板，是你吗？
- [inhales]
- [吸气]
[exhales]
[呼气]
SpongeBob, I thought
you split the scene, hipster.
海绵宝宝，我以为
你分裂了场景，时髦。
- What happened here?
- 这里发生了什么？
- Well, I had to close down
the Krusty Krab
- 好吧，我不得不关闭
蟹堡王
since you weren't around
to make the Krabby Patties.
因为你不在身边
制作蟹黄肉饼。
- Close down the Krusty Krab?
- 关掉蟹堡王？
- Yeah, I was just being
a capitalist tool.
- 是的，我只是在
资本主义的工具。
But it's all groovy now.
但现在一切都很时髦了。
I'm a far out hippie,
我是一个彻底的嬉皮士
and I'm flying
my freak flag high.
我正在飞翔
我的怪胎旗帜高高升起。
* *
**
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
Making Krabby Patties
was my number one
制作蟹肉饼
是我的第一名
favorite thing ever
to do in the whole world.
曾经最喜欢的事情
在全世界做。
- Bummer, right?
- 真糟糕，对吧？
Let's dance our cares away, man.
让我们用舞蹈来消除我们的忧虑吧，伙计。
* *
**
- Do you think that maybe
we could reopen the Krusty Krab
- 你认为也许
我们可以重新开放 Krusty Krab
and go back to how things were?
并回到原来的样子？
[record scratches]
【记录划痕】
- I thought you'd never ask!
- Yeah!
- 我以为你永远不会问！
- 是的！
But Mr. Krabs, what about
our new hippie friends?
但是蟹老板，那又如何呢？
我们的新嬉皮朋友？
- They say they need
to be somewhere warm, right?
- 他们说他们需要
去一个温暖的地方，对吗？
I have an idea.
我有一个主意。
* *
**
- You know what?
- 你知道吗？
That Old Man Krabs wasn't
such a bad dude after all.
蟹老翁不是
毕竟是个坏家伙。
[gurgling]
[淙淙]
- [laughs]
Whoa.
- [笑]
哇哦。
- Someone just crashed
our new pad.
- 有人刚刚坠毁
我们的新垫。
- [moaning]
- [呻吟]
[splashing]
[溅]
- Yo, bro, potato?
- 哟，兄弟，土豆？
- Oh, thanks, man.
-哦，谢谢，伙计。
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
* *
**
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Hippies!
嬉皮士！
[light twangy music]
[轻快的鼻音音乐]
* *
**